片名：父輩的旗幟
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
看在上帝份上！醫務兵！
For God sakes! Corpsman!
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
親愛的  怎麼了？
Honey, what's wrong?
每個傻蛋都自以為明白戰爭 是怎麼回事
Every jackass thinks he knows what war is.
尤其是那些沒親身體驗過的
Especially those who've never been in one.
我們喜歡美好而簡單的事物
We like things nice and simple,
善良和邪惡  英雄和惡棍
good and evil, heroes and villains.
很多人兩者兼具
There's always plenty of both.
大多時候 他們不同我們所想像
Most of the time, they are not who we think they are.
他在哪？
Where is he?
在哪… 他在哪？他在哪？
Where... Where is he? Where is he?
布萊德利先生？
Mr. Bradley?
布萊德利先生？你還好麼?
Mr. B? You okay?
他在哪？誰在哪？
Where is he? Where is who?
他在哪？他去哪堣F？ 在哪…他在哪？
Where is he? Where did he go? Where... Where is he?
好 就呆在這兒 好麼
All right. Just stay right here, okay?
我去叫救護車 會沒事的
I'm gonna call an ambulance. It'll be okay.
他在哪？
Where is he?
很多我認識的人不願說 過去的事情
Most guys I knew would never talk about what happened over there.
可能是因為他們正在試圖忘掉 那些事
Probably 'cause they're still trying to forget about it.
他們確實不認為自己是英雄
They certainly didn't think of themselves as heroes.
他們死去  沒有鮮花和掌聲
They died without glory.
也沒能留下照片
Nobody has taken their pictures.
只有他們的戰友知道 他們做了些什麼
Only their buddies knew what they did.
我告訴大家說他們是為國捐軀的
I'd tell their folks they died for their country.
其實是不是我也不確定
I'm not sure that was it.
那天照了很多照片
Now, there were plenty other photos taken that day,
但沒人想再多看一眼
but none anybody wanted to see.
我們在戰爭中的所見所聞 所作所為
What we see and do in war,
之殘酷  是不可思議的
the cruelty, is unbelievable.
但我們總得找出點意義來
But somehow we gotta make some sense of it.
這樣 我們就需要一個淺顯的事實
To do that, we need a easy to understand truth
還有一些文字
and damn few words.
膠片毀了
Film's ruined.
我不知道 這一卷看起來是完好的
I don't know. This one looks all right.
如果你能照下一張相片
And if you can get a picture...
這年頭 一張照片就能影響戰爭結局
Now, the right picture can win or lose a war.
你肯定想看看這個
You're gonna want to see this.
看看越南吧
Look at Vietnam.
那張南越軍官
The picture of that South Vietnamese officer
一槍把那傢伙打了個腦漿迸裂 崩！
blowing that fella's brains out of the side of his head, whammo!
完了
That was it.
戰爭就輸了
The war was lost.
我們當時只是死撐著 裝作還沒輸罷了
We just hung around trying to pretend it wasn't.
那天還照了很多其他的照片 大多數都沒什麼新意
Took a lot of other pictures that day. None of them made a difference.
謝謝
Thanks. Appreciate it.
聽上去很荒誕  不過還就是發生了
Sounds ridiculous, but it happened.
當時國家快破產了
Country was bankrupt.
人們冷嘲熱諷  厭倦戰爭
People were becoming cynical and tired of war.
老天啊 那是哈倫
Oh, my Lord, that's Harlon!
在哪?
Where?
就在這 正在插旗子這個就是你哥哥
Right there. Planting that flag, that's your brother.
媽 你不就看見了個後背嗎
Ma, all you can see is his behind.
那是他的背 我一點點把他喂大的 我知道我兒子
And that's his. I powdered and diapered it, I know my son.
就是他  叫你爸來
That's him. Go get your father.
爸  媽說她在報紙上看見 哈倫的屁股啦
Daddy, Ma's got a picture of Harlon's keister in the paper.
管好你的嘴巴  小年輕
You watch your mouth, young man.
謝謝
Thank you.
僅僅一張照片  讓形勢出現逆轉
One photo, almost all on its own, turned that around.
它上了各大報紙的頭條
It's on the front page of every major paper.
超過200家報社要求 刊登這張照片
Over 200 dailies and they're all flooded with requests for prints.
我們可能得把他們找出來
I think we might have found it.
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
我去把他弄過來 不行 你不能去
I gotta go get him. Oh, no, you don't.
伊基  我必須去
Iggy, I gotta go.
我的看法正好相反
I have a whole different theory.
他那麼需要救護 他會來找我們的
He wants medical attention bad enough, he'll come to us.
閉上嘴乖乖趴那兒別動 你個婊子養的大懶蛋
Shut up and crawl over here, you lazy son-of-a-bitch!
照明彈一滅我就去
As soon as that flare goes out.
廢話 那好 我跟你去 不
Crap. Okay, well, I'll go with you. No.
你想把我丟在這婸
You're actually gonna leave me here?
我馬上回來 你繼續射擊  我得馬上走
I'll be right back, just shoot some people. I gotta go.
老天
Oh, God.
沒事 沒事的
Okay, it's okay.
別碰傷口 別碰傷口
Don't touch them. Don't touch them.
把手放那邊 我來 我做
Get your hands out of there. Let me do that. I'll do it, okay?
別看 頭扭過去 眼睛看著我
Don't look. Keep your head back. Keep your eyes on me.
好的 看著我 我會解決的 我會治好你的
All right, look at me. I'll get it. I'll take care of it.
我們現在給你纏繃帶 我們來照顧你
We'll get this bandage on you. We'll get you taken care of.
我們把你運到後方去 好麼
And we'll get you down to the bottom, all right?
你會沒事的
Look, you're gonna be fine.
沒事了
It's okay.
我來 我來
I'll do that. I'll do that.
好 用力壓住
Here, put some pressure on that.
手放上面 用力加壓
Put your hands on top and put some pressure on it.
頭扭過去  保持呼吸
Keep your head back. Keep breathing.
看著我 好麼 只要你看著…
Keep looking at me, all right? Just keep looking at...
醫生
Doc.
救我
Help me.
好的  沒事
All right. Okay.
（注射嗎啡）感覺怎麼樣
How's that feel?
感覺不錯 是麼？好的
It feels good. It does? All right.
好 好的
Good. All right.
我去找擔架把你抬下去 我馬上回來
I'm gonna go get a stretcher and get you down to the beach. I'll be right back.
我沒事
I'm all right.
去幫其他傷員吧
Go and help someone who's hurt.
好的 堅持住
All right. Hold on there.
他去哪了？ 誰？
Where'd he go? Who?
剛才在這堛漕滬 伊基 他去哪了？
The guy who was right here, Ignatowski. Where did he go?
你跳錯坑了吧 我才沒有跳錯坑
I think you jumped in the wrong hole. I didn't jump in the wrong hole!
剛剛他還在這 現在他哪去了？
He was right here, now where the hell is he?
伊基！
Iggy!
你閉嘴吧  你想讓全島的日本人 都朝我們開火麼
You shut up. You want every Jap on the island shooting at us?
伊基！
Iggy!
塔拉瓦營地  1944年12月
我靠
Holy shit.
他們指望我們來爬這個？
They expect us to climb this?
應該差不多吧
Or something just like it.
那 你覺得 他們想把我們 送到什麼地方去？
So, where you think they're sending us?
好像是沙漠吧  富蘭克林
I think it's the desert, Franklin.
這可說不通啊
Well, that makes no sense at all.
這就叫軍事心理學
Well, it's just military psychology.
你要去沙漠執行任務的話 他們就在火山上訓練你
They always train you for the desert on a volcano.
你這是開玩笑的吧
Now you're just having fun with me.
哈倫 帶你的人到右邊去
Harlon, take your men right.
注意搜索貝都因人 是 長官
Watch for Bedouins. Yes, sir.
什麼叫貝都因人？ 就是騎駱駝的人
What's a Bedouin? It's a guy with a camel.
老天爺 原來我們還真有可能到沙漠去
Well, Jeez Louise, maybe we are going to the desert.
你看  你把頭盔向右歪著戴 那要是子彈從左邊來呢？
Now, you tilt that to the right, but what if the bullet comes from the left?
子彈才不會從左邊來 你認識左撇子日本人麼？
Bullets don't come from the left. You know any left-handed Japs?
你這麼干就跟穿著鞋去 洗澡一樣蠢
That makes about as much sense as you showering with your shoes on.
你連自己為什麼這麼做 都不知道 是不是？
You don't even know why you do it, do you?
我不告訴你就代表我不知道麼？
'Cause I don't tell you mean I don't know?
你不就是模仿麥克麼
You do it 'cause Mike does it.
我問他去
I'll ask him.
你在家也理發麼？
So you cut hair back home?
有時候吧
Some.
醫生 你是專業理髮師 對吧？
Training to be a barber, are you, Doc?
不是 就學了一點兒
No, I just studied it a little.
不是正規學校學的？
But not in barber school?
不是啊
Nope.
糟糕 讓我猜猜 海因斯要贏
Gosh. Let me guess, Hayes is winning.
酋長西亭布爾可不是我害死的啊
Chief, I had very little to do with Sitting Bull's death,
酋長 - 艾拉 海因斯的昵稱 西亭布爾 - 北美蘇人印弟安人首領
所以你就別拿我出氣了
so maybe you could stop taking it out on me.
哪兒跟哪兒的事啊 皮馬人當時可是站在白人一邊的
Different tribe. The Pimas fought on the side of the white man.
皮馬人 - 北美印第安人的一個部族
現在看來真有遠見 就是有遠見
See, now that's smart. That is smart.
是啊 所以現在我們族人 比較好過
Yeah. Worked real good for us.
大家好運
Good luck, fellas.
嘿 晚安 林勃
Hey, good night, Lindberg.
死人 他給死人理發
Dead bodies. He cuts hair on dead bodies.
這算什麼？連我都知道
What? Even I knew that.
誰還玩牌？ 我來 我也來
Who's in? Oh, I'm in. I'm in.
老老實實坐著不動 你就能省很多勁了
It must be a lot easier with them not moving around and all.
確實 是啊
There's that. Yeah.
知道我一直在想什麼麼?
You know what I been thinking?
他們總說 讓我們大家成為好兄弟
Well, they been telling us we need to buddy up
我覺得我們就可以 做個兄弟
and I think we'd make pretty good buddies.
你怎麼知道我們會是好兄弟
And how do you figure that?
嗯 因為 我們共同點很多
Well, you know, in that we have a lot in common.
那你到底為什麼給死人剪頭呢？
So, why do you cut dead people's hair, anyway?
我在一家殯儀館當學徒
I'm studying to work in a funeral home.
你把這個告訴過很多人麼？
You tell a lot of people that?
你進陸戰隊 就是因為它的制服最帥？
You actually chose the Marines because they got the best uniform?
想成英雄的話 起碼得先看起來像個英雄吧
No sense being a hero if you don't look like one.
Ｊ
Ｊ Jacks.
Ｑ
Ｑ Queens.
靠
Shit.
你服役期間就是玩玩牌麼 酋長？
Do anything on that reservation but play cards, Chief?
都給我聽好了 可憐的陸戰隊員們！
All right, listen up, you sorry bunch of leathernecks!
明天我們練習登陸
We practice going over the side tomorrow
也就是說我們不用在這小地方 再呆下去了
which means we ain't long for this piece of rock.
好
All right!
還有個事 自慰專用紙沒配齊的人
One more thing, any man who doesn't have his masturbation papers in order
明天晚上之前最好去申請 否則他就不能出任務
better get them signed by tomorrow night or he ain't going overseas.
我已經有了 我也有了
I got mine already. Oh, yeah. I'm square.
等等 為什麼我現在才知道？
Wait. Why am I just hearing about this?
那你活該倒霉  富蘭克林 我好話不說第二遍
That's horseshit, Franklin. I don't have to repeat everything twice for you.
不對啊 我怎麼沒聽說過 自慰專用紙的事呢？
No, I didn't hear nothing about no masturbating papers.
聽說最近正鬧短缺呢
Heard they were running short.
好啊 大家都不告訴我是吧 行啊你們
You know, nobody tells me nothing. That's real nice, guys.
這樣 你趕緊到記錄員那去一趟
All right, get your ass over to the officer in charge of records.
可能他還有發剩下的
Maybe he got some more left.
煙留下  牌我替你接著打 謝謝啊 麥克
Leave your smokes. I'll play for you. Thanks, Mike.
聽好 到時候他肯定會說你白癡 你就表現的男人一點 明白？
Listen, he calls you an idiot, you take it like a man, okay?
牢牢記住  一定得簽了字再走
Just do not leave without signing them.
非常感謝 中士. 去吧
I appreciate it, Sergeant. You got it.
你頭髮怎麼搞的 瑞尼？
What the hell happened to your hair, Rene?
跟他媽屍體一樣
Look like a goddamn corpse.
隨時保持三個地方和繩索 連在一塊兒
Three points of contact on that rope at all times.
再來四個 爬下去
Next four. Over the side.
走 別停下
Let's go. Keep moving.
再來四個 爬下去
Next four, over the side.
眼睛看著 自己下面那個人
Just keep your eye on the guy below you.
那就夠了
That's all you gotta look at.
看著我 醫生 看著我
Watch me, Doc, just watch me.
隨時保持三個地方和繩索 連在一塊兒
Keep three points of contact on the rope at all times.
看 沒什麼大不了的
You see? No big thing.
一步一步下 手抓緊繩子
Just one step at a time and keep your hands on the vertical rope.
記住 下到船上以後就鬆手
Remember, once you're in the boat move away from the rope.
隨時保持三個地方和繩索 連在一塊兒就行
Just make sure you keep three points of contact on the rope.
交給我！
I got him!
好 把那人撈上來
All right, get that man out of the water.
幫個忙
Give me a hand.
抓住他背包
Grab his pack.
別擔心他 醫生
Don't worry about him, Doc.
好了 多可笑 大家繼續
All right, quit skylarking! Keep it moving!
他會沒事的
He'll be fine.
我們的目標 就是某小島
Our target, Island X,
是個又臭又醜又髒的小島 叫硫磺島
is an ugly, smelly, dirty little scab of rock called lwo Jima.
就是「硫磺之島」的意思 因為硫磺味兒才得的名
It means "Sulfur Island," which accounts for the smell.
我覺得 看起來就像是塊 燒焦了的豬排
Looks sort of like a burnt pork chop, you ask me.
狂轟濫炸20天之後
After 20 straight days of bombing
島上已經寸草不生了
you won't find a blade of grass or a twig on it.
可不怎麼好看
It wasn't that pretty to start with.
上校？
Captain?
硫磺島只有5.5英里長 2.5英里寬
Lwo's just five-and-a-half miles long, two-and-a-half wide.
在這埵陪茯藎_ 叫做折缽山
There's a lump down at the bottom. That's Mount Suribachi.
在你們面前的這份地圖 這個島是白色的
On the maps in front of you the island is white.
實際情況不是這樣
Not much of it.
黑點代表 已知的敵人炮位
The black dots represent known enemy emplacements.
岸防炮 高平兩用炮
Coastal defense guns, dual-mount dual-purpose guns,
構成了火炮防線
covered artillery emplacements.
有散兵壕 散兵坑 反坦克炮
Rifle pits, foxholes, antitank guns
機槍 碉堡 暗堡 還有偽裝好的其他建築
machine guns, blockhouses, pillboxes, and earth-covered structures.
我看不到兵營或者是其他建築
I don't see any barracks or any other structures.
對
That's right.
我們還不知道原因
And we still don't know why.
這可不是一個尋常的小島
Now, this isn't just any island to them.
這可不是塔拉瓦島 關島 提尼安島 或者塞班島
This isn't Tarawa, Guam, Tinian, or Saipan.
這堿O日本人的地盤 是他們的神聖領土
This is Japanese soil, sacred ground.
一萬兩千名日本守軍 防守8平方英里
Twelve thousand Japanese defenders in eight square miles.
他們可不會禮貌地離開 先生們
They will not leave politely, gentlemen.
說服他們離開得靠我們
It's up to us to convince them.
28連會在綠灘登陸
The 28th will land here at Green Beach.
8連會在這媯n陸支援
The 8th Ammo Company will land here to re-supply.
折缽山上的炮位是最大的麻煩
The Suribachi's guns are the biggest problem.
它的射程可以覆蓋全島
They can hit any point on the island.
拿不下那塈畯抴N全完
We're sitting ducks until we take them out.
那是我們的份內事
That's our job.
我們奔襲小島 直取敵巢 一擊致命
We cut across the island, right at the base, slit its throat, lop off its head.
我們拿下那座山
And we take that mountain.
我們拿下那座山 就拿掉了他們的大炮
We take that mountain, we take their big guns.
就拿掉了他們的眼珠
We take their eyes.
好 進入航路 跟著我
Okay, I'm heading in. Follow me.
咱們給陸戰隊好好演一場
Let's put a good show on for the Marines.
拉近 拉近甲板
Close it up. Take it right down to the deck.
好樣的！
Yeah, boys!
左舷有人落水！
Man overboard portside!
看到他沒有？
See him?
扔根繩子過來！
Throw me a line!
他在那
He's right there.
他在哪？ 往遠處看 遠處
Where is he? Watch out, watch out, watch out.
夏威夷在那邊呢！
Hawaii's that way!
接著踩水 馬克 等我們回來的時候接你！
Just keep paddling, Mac, we'll catch you on the way back!
堅持一會兒 他們會放救生艇 下去的
Hold on, they're gonna lower a raft!
他們不會停的
They're not gonna stop.
什麼？
What?
誰都不會停的  停不下來了
None of them are. They can't.
「不拋棄每個人」這口號算完了
So much for "No man left behind."
長官 進來
Sir. Come on in.
我想做點人事變動
Look, I've had to make a few other changes.
我準備提你當排長
I'm promoting you to platoon sergeant.
謝謝 長官 我很感激 不必
Thank you, sir. I appreciate it. You bet.
問題是  我已經告訴他們 我會一直陪在他們身邊的
Trouble is, I already told my men I'd see them through this.
你這是在演詹姆斯·卡格尼那齣戲是吧？
That your James Cagney impersonation?
我聽過更好的
'Cause I've heard better.
我會多加練習的
Well, I'll keep practicing, then.
聽著 你又不是新手
Look, this isn't your first time through this.
你不必證明什麼 是的 長官
You don't need to prove anything. No, sir.
你不是最好的
You're not the best sergeant I've ever had,
只是活著的人堶掖怞n的
you're just the best one that's still walking.
布勞克人不錯 是 長官 確實如此
Block's a good man. Yes, sir, he is.
大家都知道他 他進房間都不用打招呼
The men know him, he can step right in.
這件事前前後後我都想過了
You know, I have actually thought this through.
做排長可以讓你更安全
Platoon sergeant puts you further away from the bullets.
但是我已經承諾過了 長官
I already gave them my word, sir.
我還承諾過我會把他們 全都帶回家見媽媽
I told them I'd bring them all home to their mothers
也就是說 我對他們中間的一半人都撒謊了 我不能再對另一半人撒謊
which means I already lied to half of them. Can't lie to the rest.
那他們怎麼樣？ 他們會沒事的
How are your men? They'll do fine.
蓋格南可能是個例外
Except maybe Gagnon.
就是那個像蒂龍·鮑爾的傢伙？
Our own Tyrone Power?
是 長官 他人不壞 但是確實上不了前線
Yes, sir. He's a good man, just might be better use further back from the lines.
那我就讓他當通信兵吧
I'll use him as a runner.
好的 謝謝 長官
All right. Thank you, sir.
那你出去吧
Now get out of here.
聽到好消息了麼 醫生？ 我們會第一波登陸的
Hear the good news, Doc? We're going in with the first waves.
嘿 你敢再幹一次 我就把你腦袋擰下來
Hey, you do that again I'll take your head off!
你個方腦袋
Fucking dominoes.
伊基 你聽到過壞消息麼？
Iggy, have you ever heard news you considered to be bad?
醫生 第一批下船作戰
The first ones off the ship, Doc.
就是說我們不用再爬下船去了
Means we don't go over the side of the ship.
我們只要跳上車 他們就把我們送過去了
We hop on a tractor, they drive us right there.
我靠 那不是好消息麼
Oh, shit, that is good news.
你才明白啊？我就說嘛
You see? What'd I tell you?
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
快看
Look at that.
我們正痛宰他們呢
We're killing them!
我們正痛宰他們呢  醫生
We're killing them, Doc.
說好是10天的炮火準備
I was promised 10 days of shelling.
現在你只給我3天 還說你已經盡力了？
You're giving me three and saying that's the best you can do?
我不管！ 炮火準備少於 10天的話
I don't give a shit! My men hit that beach with less than 10
就等著我用棺材把他們送回家吧
and I'll be taking them home to their mamas in buckets!
好啊  我算是明白了
Yeah, I know exactly why.
原來是海軍堥漕ヴa埵 點罈罈罐罐的人
Because every Navy man with a scrambled egg on his chest
想把我們扔在這兒 自己去日本
wants to offload us here and sail to Japan
去看大結局  對吧？
so they can be there for the big finish,
然後跟他們的孩子們說 他們自己就把天皇活捉了 是吧？
tell their kids they captured the Emperor all by themselves.
我們不拿下這個小破島 你們就永遠去不了日本！
Well, you aren't going to Japan unless we take this piece of shit island!
這些小島就是我們眼堛漕諢I
These little pricks are dug in!
很好 萬分感謝 吉姆 三天的時間真是太他媽好了
Okay, appreciate that, Jim. Three days is a fucking beautiful thing.
磨刀麼？
Sharpen your knife or bayonet?
我的沒問題
I'm okay.
磨刀麼？
Sharpen your knife or bayonet?
老天 伊基 讓我自己呆會兒行不？
Jesus, Iggy, just leave me alone, all right?
你們呢? 匕首? 刺刀? 磨一下？
How about you guys? Knife? Bayonet? Kick in the ass?
你的呢 醫生？ 磨磨刀？
How about you, Doc? Sharpen your knife?
我都磨了三遍了
You sharpened it three times already.
那就再讓我給你磨磨
Well, then I better make sure I didn't nick it.
好人啊 醫生
Good man, Doc.
嘿 醫生 嗯
Hey, Doc. Yeah.
登陸以後 別太張揚你身上 這些急救包
When we land, try not to wave this kit around too much.
那邊有些神槍手 專門打這樣的人
They got sharpshooters that are trained to look for them.
他們知道 如果他們幹掉一個醫務兵
And they know that if they take out a corpsman
好多士兵就會缺乏救助而死 明白麼？
another dozen Marines will die unattended. All right?
好的 麥克
Okay, Mike.
好 就停在這兒
Yeah, right there.
把門關上  看在上帝份上
Close the damn door. For God's sake.
哈 說得好像那樣就沒事了一樣
Yeah, like that's gonna help.
那是你女朋友麼 酋長？
That your girlfriend, Chief?
肯定是個超級印第安美女
Bet she's a pretty damn good-looking squaw.
你肯定想你女朋友 還有你們溫暖的小窩棚了
Bet you're missing her, and that little wigwam of yours.
（日方廣播）歡迎 來硫磺島 作客的陸戰隊員們
Welcome, all Marines off lwo Jima.
我們期待已久…
We have a long-time wait...
看看他們對犯人都做了些什麼
It's what they do to prisoners,
這還算是好的 老天
at least the lucky ones. Jesus.
牛仔 我要是你 才不會舉白旗呢
If I were you, cowpokes, I wouldn't think about waving a white bandanna.
（日方廣播）可憐的陸戰隊員們 無緣無故  離家千里
Poor Marines, so far from home for no good reason.
想想家中苦苦期盼的女友…
Think of your girls back home, waiting for you.
但女孩孤身一人  怎能熬過 漫漫長夜
But a girl cannot stay home every night.
想一想 她們今晚會和誰同床共枕？
So who do you think they're with tonight?
她會讓他吻她麼？ 他會在你的葬禮上去安慰她麼？
And will she let him kiss her? And will he comfort her at your funeral?
這段甜美的音樂可以讓你們 想起家中的女友
This sweet music is to make you think of your girls back home
苦苦思念你們的女友
who are missing you.
本日節目到此結束 明晚再會
This is all for now. I'll see you tomorrow night.
士兵們！
Gunners!
行動！行動！ 衝上防波堤！
Move, let's go! Let's go, get up on the berm!
士兵們！
Gunners!
安全！
We're clear!
衝上防波堤！
Get up the berm!
貝克連 行動！
Baker Company, move out!
看到二排了麼? 沒有
Seen Second Platoon? I don't see them.
一班！行動！
First Squad, move it out!
天 這地方真臭
God, this place reeks.
上上上！ 行動！
Go, go, go! Move out!
上上上！ 上上上！ 丟掉背包！上！
Go, go, go, go! Go, go! Go! Go, go! Drop your packs! Go!
安全！
All clear!
天 你忙活什麼呢? 他走丟了
Jesus, you needed some exercise? He got lost.
一百艘登陸艇衝上一個海灘 這傢伙走丟了
A hundred landing craft heading for one beach and this guy gets lost.
我們居然幹出這種好事來 天 一團糟
Now I'm glad we did. Jesus, what a mess.
他們為什麼不開火？
Any theories why they ain't shooting?
我都快變神經質了
It's getting on my nerves.
可能他們全死了吧
Maybe they're all dead.
你怎麼看 醫生？ 你認為他們全死了麼？
What do you think, Doc? You think they're all dead?
麥克 叫上六個人 把那門炮運到海灘上
Mike, take six men and bring that gun onto the beach.
二排 行動！ 保持低姿 前進
Second Platoon, let's move out! Stay down. Come on.
行動 行動！
Move! Move!
臥倒！ 找掩護！
Get down! Take cover!
行動！
Move out!
火力掩護！ 持續壓制！
Cover fire! Pour it on!
雷  趕快把火力轉向右側！
Ray, shift your fire to the right, now!
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
我先給你固定手臂 然後再來給你止痛！
I'm gonna sling your arm and then I'll give you a shot for the pain!
行動！行動！離開灘頭！
Move, move! Off the beach!
找掩護！
Take cover!
你在家埵陪茪k朋友 是吧？
You got a girl back home, Marine?
我們肯定能讓你見到她 好麼？
We're gonna make sure she sees you, all right?
壓住這個傷口！
I need pressure on this wound!
都是從哪堨捶茠滿H
Where's the fire coming from?
他們在哪？
Where are they?
注意看槍口焰  朝那兒打！
Look for a flash, shoot at it!
我們上 我們…
Let's go, let...
12點鐘方向 幹掉那個碉堡
Twelve o'clock, take out the bunker!
你完了！
You're over!
三班 衝上去 行動！
Third Squad, forward! Move!
他們在哪 長官?
Where are they, sir?
10點方向有一個！ 十點方向 暗堡一個 中士！
We got ten o'clock! Ten o'clock, pillbox! Sergeant!
中士！ 我能拿下它 什麼？
Sergeant! I think I can clear that out. What?
好  你去吧 給
All right, you go. Here.
拿著 檢查武器
Take these. Check your weapon.
好了？上！掩護！
Yeah? Go! Cover!
掩護他！
Cover him!
掩護 掩護！
Cover, cover!
婊子養的
Son-of-a-bitch.
我們上 上！
Let's go! Go!
行動！
Move it out!
上上上！
Go, go, go!
臥倒 臥倒 臥倒！
Down, down, down!
清除
It's clear.
幹得好
Good work.
你不是說清除了麼？
I thought you said it was clear!
剛才是這樣！
It was!
靠 估計是又換人了
Shit, I guess they're not in there firing at us then.
林勃！
Lindberg!
到！
Yeah!
燒了它！
Light it up!
艾斯 我掩護你！
I'll cover you, Ice!
掩護個屁！ 已經有這麼多人在開槍了！
Don't cover shit! There's already enough people shooting!
中一槍我就變成火人了
One bullet and this thing goes up like a Roman candle!
上！ 停火！
Go! Shift fire!
大家停火！
Shift your fire!
上 上！ 大家停火！
Go, go! Shift your fire!
大家停火！
Shift your fire!
上！ 行動！
Go! Move it out!
目標清除！ 保持低姿！ 等待支援！
Hit the deck! Stay down! Wait for support!
真是一場惡戰
Is this a bad battle or what?
是他媽一場屠殺
It's a fucking slaughter.
老天
Christ Jesus!
馬上叫一個機槍小組過來！
Get a machine gun team set up over here, now!
謝天謝地！ 坦克！
Thank God! Tanks!
通信兵！把坦克叫過來！
Runner! Get those tanks up here!
我靠
Oh, shit.
臥倒！
Get down!
下士 注意左翼！
Corporal, watch your left flank!
沒坦克我們也得上！ 行動！ 行動！
Let's go without them! Move out! Move out!
伊基 你那邊抬起來一點 他快掉下來了
Iggy, you gotta lift your side, he's gonna roll off.
知道了 醫生！
Got it, Doc!
炮彈來襲！
Incoming!
上 上 上 上！
Move, move, move, move!
不要停！
Keep moving!
把那輛履帶式登陸車弄上岸！
Get that LVT up on the beach!
不要停！
Keep moving!
老弟 下一個就輪到你了 我們會帶你離開這堛
You're next, pal, we're getting you out of here.
行動！
Move it!
有好消息
Great news.
你在塔拉瓦營地先過好才有可能 因為我們就要去那兒
Maybe if you live up on Camp Tarawa, 'cause that's where we're headed.
不是關於你和我的
Not you and me.
賽佛倫斯上尉問我 還有誰在那張照片上
Captain Severance asked me who else was in that picture,
我就說 老天 我怎麼想得起來
and Christ if I could remember,
但是當時有麥克 醫生 富蘭克林 我 還有漢克·漢森
but it was Mike and Doc and Franklin and me and Hank Hansen
而且我對他說你當時也在那兒
but I just remembered, you were there, too.
我不在那兒
I wasn't there.
但你在那之前在
'Course you were.
漢克也不在 他升的是第一面旗
Neither was Hank. He raised the first flag.
那面旗子是哈倫·布勞克升起來的
It was Harlon Block that raised that one.
靠 我都跟他們說那是漢克了
Shit. I told them it was Hank.
你當時又不在那兒 聰明蛋 你怎麼知道是哈倫？
You weren't there, Mr. Smart Ass, how'd you know it was Harlon?
你跟他們說了有我麼？ 沒有 我就跟他們說我記得有你
You tell them it was me? No. Like I said, I just remembered.
很好 閉嘴吧
Good, keep your mouth shut.
他們知道照片上還有別人的 一眼便知
They know there was somebody else, you can see it in the picture.
那你找個死人頂上吧
Then pick someone dead.
他們可不想要死人 你個蠢紅番
They don't want somebody dead, you dumb redskin,
他們想把我們運回國
they want to ship us back to the States.
我跟你說什麼了？
What did I tell you?
我說我不在那兒！
I wasn't there.
聽見沒？ 好吧
You hear? All right.
冷靜點
Just settle down.
我哪兒也不去 你哪兒也不去
I'm not going anywhere. You're not going anywhere.
埃尼威托克（美國托管地）1945年4月
誰說的？
Who the hell says?
淨胡扯
This is horseshit.
你受傷了？
You wounded, son?
沒有 長官
No, sir.
那你赤手空拳殺過日本鬼子麼？
Well, did you take out a nest of Japs butt-naked with your bare hands?
你要是那麼幹過 我就把這個座位讓給你坐
'Cause if I'm gonna give up my seat to a hero
你最好能有點傳奇故事可講的
he better have a good goddamn story to tell.
沒有 長官
No, sir.
那你好自為之 因為聖誕節之前 你就會被遺忘的
Then enjoy it, 'cause they'll forget you before Christmas.
第六人（指升旗隊列中） 你知道其餘人的名字麼？
The sixth man, you got a name?
抱歉 還是記不起來
Sorry, still don't remember.
那還真是丟臉了 我跟上面保證過你知道他是誰的
It's a damn shame, 'cause I promised the Major you'd know who it was.
你要是再說不出來
Fact, you not knowing throws a doubt on you
你就很難讓人相信你自己 也是升旗手之一了
being one of the flag-raisers yourself.
乾脆大家都別尷尬 你一著陸
Since no one wants to be embarrassed, the moment you land
他們就把你送回衝繩島去
they'll turn you around, ship you off to Okinawa
在海灘上跟你的兄弟們見面
in time to meet your buddies on the beach.
所以 你還跟我兜什麼圈子 名字告訴我
So, why don't you stop screwing with me? Give me a damn name.
讓路！ 讓路！ 走開 走開！ 讓路！
Gangway! Gangway! Let's go, let's go! Gangway!
那婊子養的跑哪去了? 海因斯！ 海因斯?
Where the hell is that son-of-a-bitch? Hayes! Hayes?
海因斯你個紅鬼 趕緊給我過來！
Hayes, get your red ass over here!
搞得我好像在自己眼皮底下
Make me look like I don't know what my own men are doing
都不知道自己手下的人埵陪 升旗手似的
with a flag the size of my mother's house?
他媽的 艾拉 你不該對我撒謊
God damn it, Ira, you shouldn't have lied to me.
你讓我看起來像個白癡
You made me look like a complete asshole.
我們在這兒會想你的 好運
We're gonna miss you around here. Good luck.
現在你的名字也上報紙了
Now your name's in the paper, too.
你的醫生剛才說 我們要推遲你的手術
Just heard your doctor say we're postponing your operation.
你會被運回國的
You're being shipped back to the mainland.
每個看過照片的人都以為 插旗就意味著勝利
Everybody who saw that picture thought planting the flag meant victory.
他們只想知道那個 勝利
That's all they wanted to know. Victory.
那張照片照了幾個星期以後 照片堶惜@半的人就都死了
Within a few weeks of that picture being taken, half the men in it were dead.
漢森太太！ 漢森太太！ 您知道漢克是個英雄麼?
Mrs. Hansen! Mrs. Hansen! Did you know Hank was a hero?
您為他自豪麼 漢森太太? 他年少時品行如何?
Are you proud of him, Mrs. Hansen? What was he like as a boy?
請看這 太太
Look this way, please, ma'am.
對您的兒子您有何評價?
What do you have to say about your son?
但成為照片中的一員頗有意義
But somehow being a part of it meant something.
看著它 你就會相信 所有的犧牲並非白費
Looking at it, you could believe their sacrifice was not a waste.
是啊 我也可以想像那就是哈倫
Yeah, I might have thought that was Harlon, too.
本來就是
It is.
貝爾 他們的名字就列在這兒 那不是他
Belle, their names are right here. It's not him.
要不是你 他現在就會好好地活著 坐在這
And he would be alive and sitting right here if it wasn't for you.
看照片的時候你自己多想想吧 埃德
You think about that when you look at his picture, Ed.
我得趕緊回家換衣服
And I need to rush home and change
因為一會兒有一個州長的宴會 然後還有一個遊行
because there's the Governor's banquet and then there's the parade.
想想看 州長親自來這堥ㄖ畯
Imagine, the Governor is coming here to meet us.
現在我穿的是藍色 那麼如果…
Now, I'm wearing blue so, if...
你也要去換衣服麼? 現在我們打斷正在播出的節目
Are you going to change? We interrupt this program to bring you
播出一則由哥倫比亞廣播公司 世界新聞節目帶來的最新消息
a special news bulletin from CBS World News.
一家通訊社剛剛宣佈 羅斯福總統已經去世
A press association has just announced that President Roosevelt is dead.
總統死於腦溢血
The President died of a cerebral hemorrhage.
就目前所知 總統死於佐治亞州 溫泉療養院
All we know so far is that the President died at Warm Springs in Georgia.
更多信息將每小時送出
Further updates every hour.
今日氣溫保持穩定
Temperatures will remain the same today,
35度到40度出頭 天氣晴朗…
in the mid-30s to low 40s with clear skies.
喂?
Hello?
好的 當然
Yes. Of course.
不 我們能理解 那確實不太合適
No, we understand. It wouldn't be right.
謝謝
Thank you.
先生們 他來了 參議員博伊德先生、參議員羅布森先生
Here he is, gentlemen. Senator Boyd, Senator Robson.
參議員哈迪根先生 這是一等兵艾拉·海因斯
Senator Haddigan. I'd like you to meet Private First Class Ira Hayes.
見到你真太好了
Damn good to meet you.
認識你真令人自豪
Proud to make your acquaintance, son.
你說什麼?
Sorry?
那是皮馬族印第安語啊 你難道聽不懂自己的母語麼？
That's Pima Indian talk, boy, don't you know your own language?
費了好大勁才學會這一句
Took forever to memorize the damn gibberish.
抱歉 參議員先生 我離開 皮馬族保留地已經很久了
Sorry, I've been away from the reservation too long, Senator.
醫生 艾拉
Doc. Ira.
現在有請 硫磺島的英雄們！
And now, the heroes of lwo Jima!
該你們了 上 上 上 上 上
That's you. Go, go, go, go. Go.
請大家歡迎
Please welcome
海軍醫務兵約翰·佈雷德利
Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley,
一等兵艾拉·海因斯
Private First Class Ira Hayes,
一等兵瑞尼·蓋格南
Private First Class Rene Gagnon!
真他媽壯觀
Holy shit.
請進 請進 請進 我是巴德·葛博 財政部的
Come in, come in, come in. Bud Gurber, Treasury Department.
瑞尼·蓋格南 巴德·葛博
Rene Gagnon. Bud Gurber.
帶他們四處轉過了麼? 剛看了場精綵球賽
You showing the boys the sights? We saw a hell of a ball game.
很好 酒在那兒 自己倒吧
That's great. The bar's there, help yourself.
我給你們準備了幾張簡易的表格
I got some briefing sheets for you here,
上面有一些我們想讓你們說的話
just some simple things we want you to say.
概括起來就是「買債券吧」 不過別說太頻繁了
Mostly, "Buy bonds," can't say that too often.
你們的日程表一直在改
Itineraries, those are changing every couple minutes.
人人都想見你們
Everybody wants to meet you guys.
不少女人寄來裝著長襪的信封
I got women sending up envelopes with stockings in them,
還有用口紅寫的小紙條 這事可別外傳了 對吧？
notes written in lipstick. We won't mention that to the press, am I right?
看在上帝份上 喝一杯
Have a drink, for Christ's sake.
老天 你們剛才也都看到了吧
My God, what you boys must have seen over there.
我一直在關注著新聞
I've been watching the newsreels.
老天 我們有的忙了
Jesus Christ, that was a fight and a half.
我們要籌到大筆的錢 時間卻不充裕
So, we got a hell of a lot of money to raise, not a lot of time.
明天先去白宮 然後領你們到處轉轉
White House tomorrow, then we trot you over
去跟一大堆國會議員握手
to shake hands with a couple of hundred Congressmen
全是些一毛不拔的鐵公雞
who won't pull a penny out of their pockets.
政客都是好演員
Politicians and actors.
你把他們放到一個飯館
You put them in a restaurant together,
他們等到自己老死 都不會有人付賬
they'd die of old age before picking up the check.
下一站是紐約 時代廣場
Then New York City, Times Square,
與社會名流共進晚餐 然後就是芝加哥…
dinners with various hoi polloi, then Chicago...
這些「金星母親」是什麼人？
Who are these "Gold Star Mothers"?
那是我們對那些已死的升旗手 母親們的稱呼
That's what we're calling the mothers of the dead flag-raisers.
你們遞給每個母親一面旗子
You present each mother with a flag,
然後說幾句話 人們就會慷慨解囊
they say a few words, people will shit money.
多感人啊
It'll be so moving.
但這埵竟~克·漢森的媽媽
But this says Hank Hansen's mom.
可愛的女人 她知道你和她兒子 關係有多好
Lovely woman. She knows how close you and her son were.
他在家信中常提起你
He wrote home about you.
她是如此如此地想見到你
She is very, very much looking forward to meeting you.
漢克不在照片
Hank wasn't in the picture.
什麼？
Sorry?
漢克沒有升那面旗
Hank didn't raise that flag.
他升的是另一面 真正的那面
He raised the other one, the real flag.
什麼？ 真正的… 真正的那面？還有這個說法？
The what? The real... The real flag? There's a real flag?
是的 我們升的那面不過是 一面替補旗
Yeah, ours was the replacement flag.
第一面降下去以後我們就 把它升起來了
We put it up when they took the other one down.
你們還有誰覺得頭大的？ 你知道這個麼？
Am I the only one getting a headache here? You know about this?
登報以後我才知道的
It was after it was already in the papers.
母親們都已經接到通知了 不過…
The mothers had already been told, but...
很好 多好啊 好 太好了
That's it, that's beautiful. Yeah, that's beautiful.
那 為什麼告訴我這些？
Yeah, why tell me?
我是不是必須向1億5千萬美國人
I'm only the guy that has to explain it to 150 million Americans.
解釋清楚誰在那該死的照片上？
Who is in the goddamn picture?
你們埵酗H在 那張該死的照片上麼？
Are any of you guys in the goddamn picture?
是的 我們在那張該死的照片上
Yeah, we're in the goddamn picture.
六個人在硫磺島上升起國旗 勝利屬於我們
Six guys raising a flag over lwo Jima. Victory is ours.
你們是其中三個 是麼?
You're three of them, right?
那是第5天發生的事 先生 後來又打了35天
This was the fifth day, sir. The battle went on for 35 more.
那你們當時都做了些什麼？每天 午飯前都升一遍這該死的旗麼？
Well, what'd you do, raise a goddamn flag every time you stopped for lunch?
我能不能打他一頓?
Can I hit this guy?
別的我才不管呢 你們在照片
You know what, I don't give a shit, you're in the picture,
你們把旗升起來了 我們就是想說這個故事
you raised the flag, that's the story we're selling, boys.
你耳朵聾了麼? 漢克不在照片上 哈倫才在照片上
Are you deaf? Hank isn't in the picture. Harlon is in the picture.
那哈倫又他媽是誰？
Well, who the fuck is Harlon?
哈倫·布勞克 他媽媽才應該被邀請
Harlon Block. That's whose mother should be here if anyone's should be.
要我說 這整個事情就是一場鬧劇
You know, I think this whole damn thing is a farce, you ask me.
你知道他們怎麼稱呼這次巡迴籌款麼？ 叫做「偉大的第七屆」巡迴籌款
You know what they're calling this bond drive? The Mighty Seventh.
其實他們本來是想叫
They might've called it the
一群連子彈都買不起的窮光蛋
"We're Flat Fucking Broke And Can't Even Afford Bullets
向您討錢巡迴籌款的
"So We're Begging For Your Pennies" bond drive,
要不是這次籌款數額巨大 他們還真會那麼稱呼這次巡講
but it didn't have quite the ring. They could've called it that, though,
前四屆巡迴籌款都失敗了
because the last four bond drives came up so short
所以我們最後加印了點鈔票了事
we just printed money instead.
在華爾街上隨便問一個聰明人 他都會告訴你
Ask any smart boy on Wall Street, he'll tell you
我們的美元跟紙一樣 我們的欠債堆積如山
our dollar is next to worthless, we borrowed so much.
而且沒人再借給我們了 艦船停造
And nobody is lending any more. Ships aren't being built.
坦克停造 機槍 火箭筒 手榴彈 甚至拉鏈 統統停造
Tanks aren't being built. Machine guns, bazookas, hand grenades, zip.
你覺得這是場鬧劇？ 你想回去見你的戰友們是麼？
You think this is a farce? You want to go back to your buddies?
那上飛機之前 在口袋埵h裝點石頭
Well, stuff some rocks in your pockets before you get on the plane
因為我們只有用那個去扔日本人了
because that's all we got left to throw at the Japanese.
飛機起飛不了你也別奇怪
And don't be surprised if your plane doesn't make it off the runway
因為油箱早空了
because the fuel dumps are empty.
我們的好朋友阿拉伯人 又只肯接受黃金
And our good friends, the Arabs, are only taking bullion.
如果我們這次籌不到140億美元
If we don't raise $14 billion,
我們就全完了 戰爭這個月底就會結束
and that's million with a "B," this war is over by the end of the month.
我們跟日本人談判 他們要求什麼我們給什麼
We make a deal with the Japanese, we give whatever they want
然後我們就回家 因為我們看到 他們戰鬥過了
and we come home, because you've seen them fight,
而且還堅定不移
and they sure as shit ain't giving up.
140億美元
$14 billion.
前三屆加起來都沒有這麼多
The last three drives didn't make that much all together.
街頭巷尾的人們
People on the street corners,
看到這張照片以後 就會重燃希望
they looked at this picture and they took hope.
別問我原因 我覺得這就是張垃圾照片
Don't ask me why, I think it's a crappy picture myself.
連個正臉都看不到
You can't even see your faces.
但它告訴我們 我們可以贏得 並且正在贏得這場戰爭
But it said we can win this war, are winning this war,
我們就只是需要你們 把它的意義深挖一下
we just need you to dig a little deeper.
他們是想把錢給我們麼
They want to give us that money.
不 他們想把錢給你們
No, they want to give it to you.
但是你們 你們不願意要他們的錢 你們不願意給他們希望
But you, you don't want to ask for it. You don't want to give them hope.
你們只是想解釋 什麼這個人啦那面旗啊之類的事情
You want to explain about this person and that flag.
選擇權在你們
Well, that's your choice.
如果我們承認照片出錯 人們就會議論紛紛
Because if we admit we made a mistake, that's all anybody'll talk about
整個計劃就全完了
and that will be that.
先生們
Gentlemen.
總統先生 他們來了
Mr. President, here they are.
嗯 你們好 真高興見到你們 總統先生
Well, hello. Good to see you. Mr. President.
見到你們真高興
Darn good to see you, boys.
聽說你們打了不少硬仗 惡仗是麼
Heard you had a hell of a fight on your hands out there, hell of a fight.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
艾拉 你是從亞利桑那州 吉拉河保留地來的 是麼？
Ira, you're off the Gila River Reservation in Arizona, am I right?
是的 總統先生
Yes, Mr. President.
作為印第安人 你比我們都更像一個美國人
Being an Indian, you are a truer American than any of us.
你的族人應該會為你身上 的制服感到自豪吧
Bet your people are proud to see you wear that uniform.
非常自豪 先生
Very proud, sir.
理應如此
They should be.
謝謝你們不遠千里來華盛頓幫忙
Well, I want to thank you for coming all this way to Washington to help us out.
你們曾經拿下了太平洋上的敵山
You fought for a mountain in the Pacific
現在我要你們去拿下錢山
now we need you to fight for a mountain of cash.
希望你們不會讓我失望 不會的 先生
And I don't expect you'll let us down. No, sir.
很好 去做吧
Good. Go get it.
儀式到此結束
That's the end of this ceremony.
我們來這兒看看這張照片吧 看我能不能把你們一個個分辨出來
Let's take a look at this famous photo over here, see if I can pick you out.
啊呀 這不是你麼
My gosh. There you are.
小伙們 小伙們 這杯算我的 敬那些死去的戰友
Boys. Boys, this one's on me. To those who can't be with us.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
勞駕 蓋格南先生 能拍張照麼？
Excuse me, Mr. Gagnon. May we have your autograph?
可以啊
I suppose.
你叫什麼名字？
And your name is?
不知你們怎麼想的 我是覺得
I don't know about you, but I get the impression
我好像陪錯英雄了
I'm drinking with the wrong heroes.
你真是一個英雄 和你在一起真令我榮幸
You're such a hero. I feel honored to be in your presence.
哪堶
That's just not true.
演的多專業啊 來 敬演技派一杯
That's professional work. Here, to professionals.
在這兒 你們就是照片上的那幾個人 對吧？
Here they are. You're the guys in the photograph, right?
我聽說你們在車上
I heard you were on the train.
握握手 我是約翰·田納科
Let me shake your hands, John Tennack.
我是約翰·佈雷德利
John Bradley.
這幾個是和我一起的 剛從哈佛和耶魯畢業 都是乳臭未乾的小字輩
These boys are with me, Harvard and Yale types, didn't fight a lick.
他們的老爸都是大富翁
Pappies all rich sons-of-bitches.
跟真正的戰爭英雄握個手吧
Boys, shake hands with some real war heroes.
我先失陪一會兒
Excuse me for one moment.
你不給他們買杯喝的麼
You can buy them a drink while you're at it.
是啊 整個巡迴期間的飲料費我請
That's right. Drinks for these men all the way around.
你就是另外一個 是吧？ 我是約翰·田納科
And you're the other one, aren't you? John Tennack, Tennack Homes.
我是瑞尼·蓋格南 很高興見到你
Rene Gagnon. Pleased to meet you.
喝點什麼吧 來吧 這是我的名片
Have a drink, come on. And here's my card.
聽我說 瑞尼
Listen to me, Rene,
巡講結束 你出了名以後 只管來找我
when you get finished being famous you come see me
因為如果你能賣債券 你就能賣房子
because if you can sell bonds, you can sell homes.
現在他們早就不建造房子了 改成配送房子了
Now, they're not gonna build homes anymore, they're gonna deliver them.
你聽說過活動房屋麼？ 沒有 先生
You heard of prefab homes? No, sir.
你會的 留著名片 到時候來找我 明白麼？
Well, you will. And you hang on to that card and you come see me, you hear?
好麼？肯定的
All right? Certainly will.
好的
All right.
我這算是表態了吧 醫生
This sure takes it, huh, Doc?
如果麥克他們能看見我們的話
If Mike and the guys could see us.
是啊 他們肯定覺得難以置信
Yeah, they'd hardly believe it, would they?
哈倫！
Harlon!
富蘭克林！
Franklin!
你能想像富蘭克林
Can you imagine Franklin
就在這輛火車
on this train
用全銀的餐具在餐車吃東西麼
eating at the dining car with all the silver?
我們不應該在這 醫生
We shouldn't be here, Doc.
（歌詞）主的節日即將來臨
There's gonna be a Hallelujah Day
在外的青年回到家園
When the boys have all come home to stay
萬千樂隊一齊奏響
And a million bands begin to play
我們跳起勝利波爾卡
We'll be dancing the Victory Polka
當我們點起自由的火炬
And when we've lit the torch of liberty
照亮遠方那昏睡的大地
In each blacked-out land across the sea
艾拉！ 嘿 艾拉！ 聽說那張照片是擺拍的
Ira! Hey, Ira! We heard the picture was posed!
什麼？
What?
聽說那張照片是擺拍的！
We heard you posed the picture!
嘿 醫生！
Hey, Doc!
我們真了不起 醫生！
We're bigger than life, Doc!
當女孩和男孩分手
And we'll heave a mighty sigh
我們發出沉重的嘆息
When each gal can kiss the boy she kissed goodbye
他們邁過第五街
And they'll come marching down Fifth Avenue
聯合國來把他們檢閱
The United Nations in review
當夢想終於成真
When this lovely dream has all come true
我們跳起勝利波爾卡
We'll be dancing the Victory Polka
幹得漂亮
Good job.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝 女孩們
Thank you, girls!
現在
And now,
這奡N有大家期待已久的人
here are the men you've been waiting to meet,
能帶來好運的人
the men in white.
在我身後的人們 就是硫磺島的英雄們！
Right behind me here, the heroes of lwo Jima,
一等兵瑞尼·蓋格南
Private First Class Rene Gagnon,
一等兵艾拉·海因斯
Private First Class Ira Hayes,
還有海軍醫務兵約翰·佈雷德利
and Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley!
謝謝
Thank you.
很高興大家在晚上來到這 支持我們
It's good of you people to come out tonight in support of the war effort.
我們確實需要你們購買債券 這是一定的
We really need you to buy bonds, that's for sure.
沒有你們的幫助 我們就不能贏得戰爭
'Cause we can't win the war without your help.
儘管我們被人稱為硫磺島英雄
As far as us being the heroes of lwo Jima,
但那不是事實
that's just not the case.
我們其實沒做什麼
We really didn't do much at all.
尤其是他…
Especially him.
尤其是我
Especially me.
我只是個通信兵 就這麼簡單
I was just a runner. That's it.
我們升起了一面旗子
We put up a flag.
旗桿很重 所以我們有好幾個人
The pole we attached it to was heavy, so it took a number of us.
我們正巧在升旗的時候 被拍了下來
We had our picture taken doing it.
真正的英雄 已經死在了那座小島上
The real heroes are dead on that island.
如果你們踴躍購買債券來紀念他們 我們將會非常感激 謝謝
And we'd appreciate it if you bought bonds in honor of them. Thank you.
你身邊爆炸過手榴彈麼 艾拉？
Jump on any grenades, Ira?
你像我一樣端掉過碉堡麼？
Take out any machine gun nests I missed?
起碼我還開過槍
At least I fired my weapon.
你得了吧
All right, knock it off.
你打中過什麼？ 當時你是不是喝多了？
You hit anything or were you too drunk then, too?
你說什麼？
What?
別！停手！
Guys! Come on!
停手 別來了
Stop it. Knock it off.
（歌詞）戴高帽的高個男人 站在路中央
The tall man with the high hat will be coming down your way
聽到他的叫嚷 就趕緊把存款取出銀行
Get your savings out when you hear him shout
「買債券麼?」
"Any bonds today?"
買債券麼?
Any bonds today?
我銷售的是自由的債券
Bonds of freedom that's what I'm selling
買債券麼?
Any bonds today?
瑞尼 這 坐在他們兩個人中間
Rene, right here. Sit between these two boys.
（歌詞）自由之人現在降臨
Here comes the freedom man
請你今天為自由買一份單
Asking you to buy a share of freedom today
他們需要我們的幫助
...for us and they need our help.
如果你真的去想的話 你就會發現
And, if you think about it, I think you'll realize
購買更多的債券 不只是一件正確的事
that buying more bonds is not just the right thing to do
也是你唯一能做的事
but the only thing to do.
是的 戰爭已經持續了太久
Yes, this war has gone on too long.
生命已經付出了太多 它的代價…
We have given too many lives. And its cost...
要淋巧克力還是草莓 草莓
Chocolate or strawberry, sir? Strawberry.
…已經是那麼的高昂
...has been far too high.
但如果我們現在動搖
But if we waver now,
如果我們不再竭盡所能 傾盡全力
if we don't dig deep and give more than we think we can
那麼之前的所有犧牲 就全都白費了
then those sacrifices would be wasted...
要淋巧克力還是草莓 先生？
Chocolate or strawberry, sir?
所有那些逝去的生命 就全都只是徒勞了
...and those lives lost in vain.
行動！ 上 上！
Let's move! Go, go!
六號 我是二號 完畢 坦克都到哪去了？
Easy Six, this is Easy Two, over. Where the hell are our tanks?
陷在沙子堣F 上尉說沒有坦克我們也得上
Stuck in the sand. Captain says you're to go without them.
天啊
Christ.
你幹得可真不錯啊 瑞尼
That's real good work you're doing there, Rene.
好的 準備行動 傳話下去
All right, prepare to move out. Pass the word.
二排！ 行動 行動 行動！
Second Platoon! Move! Move! Move!
好 二排 動身！ 行動！
All right, Second Platoon, on your feet! Let's move out!
你個蠢驢
Jackass.
行動！
Let's move out!
上 上！ 上 上 上！
Go, go! Move, move, move!
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
二排 行動！
Second Platoon, move out!
醫生！
Doc!
醫生 離開那兒！
Doc, get out of there!
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
醫生！
Doc!
醫生 趕緊給我離開那兒！
Doc, get the hell out of there!
大家請注意
May I have your attention, please.
開往紐約城 波士頓
Train number 48 with service from New York City, Boston,
紐約州羅徹斯特市
Rochester, New York,
俄亥俄州托萊多市和印第安納州南本德市的 第48次列車 現已在第7道進站
Toledo, Ohio, and South Bend, Indiana is now arriving on Track 7.
第48次列車現已在第7道進站
Train number 48 now arriving on Track number 7.
好 下車吧 下車
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
來吧 走
Come on, boys. Let's go.
腳下留神 太太 謝謝
Watch your step, ma'am. Thank you very much.
女士們先生們 在此我謹向大家介紹 硫磺島的英雄們
Ladies and gentlemen, may I present the heroes of lwo Jima.
海軍醫務兵 綽號「醫生」 約翰·佈雷德利
Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley.
一等兵艾拉·海因斯
Private First Class Ira Hayes.
一等兵瑞尼·蓋格南
And Private First Class Rene Gagnon.
瑞尼  那是我男朋友
Rene! That's my boyfriend!
那人是誰
Who the hell is that?
不知道
I don't know.
瑞尼  她是你女朋友麼 嘿 他們叫你什麼
Rene, is that your girl? Hey, what do they call you?
來一張怎麼樣  嘿 看看！
How about a photo? Hey, look at that!
你叫什麼 小美人 你叫什麼名字
What's your name, doll? What's your name?
嘿  她可真是個美人兒
Hey, she's a beauty.
我們去找個沙龍吧
Let's go find a saloon.
大家笑一笑 讓他們覺得物有所值
Smile, boys. Give them their money's worth.
嘿 醫生 一路下來感覺如何?
Hey, Doc, how's the tour going for you?
謝謝
Thank you.
你知道自己現在在哪婸
Where exactly are you staying?
我還不確定… 那就忘了那回事吧
I'm not sure yet. Just forget about that.
參議員先生 這位是 醫務兵約翰·佈雷德利
Senator, I'd like you to meet Corpsman John Bradley.
這就是醫生 是吧 是的 很高興見到您 參議員先生
Doc, right? Yes, sir. Nice to meet you, Senator.
真高興見到你 年輕人
Good to meet you, young man.
感謝你一直以來的所作所為
Now, we appreciate everything you've done and everything you're doing.
謝謝你 先生 不算什麼
Thank you, sir. Quite all right.
懷特中校
This is Captain White.
約翰上校 我們為你驕傲 醫務兵
Colonel Johns. We're proud of you, Corpsman.
這是麥克考特尼上校
And then Colonel McCourtney.
格林將軍 很高興見到你
Major General Green. Nice to meet you.
參議員先生 這是一等兵艾拉·海因斯
Senator, this is Private First Class Ira Hayes.
當然
Of course!
我聽說你用印第安戰斧殺那些 日本鬼子 是麼 酋長
Now I hear you used a tomahawk on those Japs. Is that true, Chief?
不是  先生
No, sir.
你說是不就完了嘛  這樣故事才 更好聽嘛
Well, tell them you did, makes a better story, huh?
幹的漂亮 這是格林中校
Attaboy. This is Captain Green.
約翰？
John?
我是麥德琳·艾薇爾 我是從照片上認出你來的 我是漢克的媽媽
Madeline Evelley. I recognize you from all the photographs. I'm Hank's mom.
真高興見到您 夫人 漢克總是提起您
It's so nice to meet you, ma'am. Hank was always talking about you.
這是一等兵瑞尼·蓋格南
This is PFC Rene Gagnon.
很高興認識你 謝謝你
Pleasure to meet you, son. Thanks for everything.
那是我的榮幸 哪堶
My pleasure. Not at all.
艾拉  這是斯坦克太太 麥克的媽媽
Ira, I'd like you to meet Mrs. Strank, Mike's mom.
這沒什麼
It's all right.
接到電報以後  我…
When I got the telegram, I...
不知來這婺蚖”リ偵
I don't know what I'm trying to say here.
知道他那天和你們在一起 看到他出現在那張照片上
Knowing he was with you that day and seeing him in that photograph,
我覺得好多了  也說不清為什麼 不過確實是這樣
I don't know why it makes me feel better, but it does.
這很愚蠢是吧 不  不是的
It's so silly, isn't it? No, it's not.
你好麼? 非常感謝
How are you, son? Thank you very much.
我們是伊利諾伊州最大的 傢俱批發商
We're the largest furniture wholesaler in Illinois.
謝謝 勞駕
Thank you. Excuse me.
（波琳:）我們會打電話給你的 謝謝  謝謝
I'll make sure he calls. Well, thank you. Thank you.
你就是瑞尼麼
Are you Rene?
是的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我是富蘭克林的母親
I'm Franklin's mother.
很榮幸見到您  夫人
It's an honor to meet you, ma'am.
我是波琳  瑞尼的女朋友
I'm Pauline, Rene's girlfriend.
你不介意吧
Would you mind?
報紙上說那就是漢克
Paper said that's Hank,
老實說我可沒看出來
and I honestly can't tell.
作為一個母親連她自己的兒子 都認不出來太說不過去了 是吧
It's horrible of a mother not to know her own son, isn't it?
但他確實在畫上 是吧
But that's him, isn't it?
嗯 夫人 說實話 當時太突然了
Well, to be honest, ma'am, it happened so quick,
一切就那麼突然發生了
and with everything that was going on
很難記得當時究竟誰站在什麼 位置上了
it's kind of hard to remember who was where.
但是…
But...
是的 我認為… 我認為他當時就站在那兒
Yeah, I think... I think that's where he was.
那是漢克
That's Hank.
謝謝你
Thank you.
不好意思
Excuse me.
您痛失愛子我深表遺憾
I'm so sorry for your loss.
原諒我們
Excuse us.
把他帶出去
Take him outside.
我是波琳
I'm Pauline.
非常高興見到你 很高興見到你
Very nice to meet you. Hi, nice to meet you.
他是我知道的最好的陸戰隊員
He was the best Marine I ever knew.
謝謝
Thank you.
你沒事吧 酋長 老天
You okay, Chief? Oh, Christ!
我沒事
I'm okay.
好啊 你看看你 你想把事情搞砸 是麼
Yeah, you look it. You're gonna screw this up, aren't you?
你想把大家的事全搞砸
You're gonna screw it up for all of us.
我來跟他講
I've got him.
睡一覺吧  艾拉
Get some sleep, Ira.
麥克 什麼事
Mike? Yeah?
看見沒有 什麼
You see this? What?
麥克 糟糕  快上
Mike! Oh, shit, go!
他殺我！
He's killing me!
嘿 醫生 他們被全滅了麼
Hey, Doc, you think they got them all?
什麼
What?
你看他們都不打我們了 可能被我們全殲了吧
Well, they're not shooting at us. Maybe we killed them all.
要不然就是他們連夜逃跑了吧
Or they ran off in the night or something.
再不然他們在等我們開始爬山
Or they're waiting for us to start climbing.
三排！ 拿上傢伙 我們爬那座山去
Third Platoon! Grab your gear, we're going up the hill.
就只有我們？ 是啊 就我們 伊基
Just us? Yeah, just us, lgg.
好的 三排 行動
All right, Third Platoon, move!
我也跟著去？
I tag along?
行啊  願意的話  你走前面 好好給我來幾個特寫
Yeah, you can lead the way if you want. Get a good shot of my face.
給你來個屁股特寫你就能出名
It's your ass I'm gonna make famous, Hank.
嘿 我也是
Hey, that'll work for me, too.
中尉
Lieutenant,
到山頂以後 把這個掛上
if you make it to the top, put this up.
是
Yes, sir.
別擔心 伊基 他們不打排頭兵的
Don't worry, Iggy. They never shoot at the first patrol.
是麼 是啊
They don't? No.
我們肯定安全到頂 因為他們不想打草驚蛇
They want us to go up to the top, signal to the others that it's okay,
等到後續大部隊上山 他們才會大開殺戒
then shoot everybody else as they come up the mountain.
是麼 是啊
Really? Yeah.
除非他們想來個殺雞儆猴
Unless of course they want to make an example of us
先給山下的弟兄一個下馬威
and discourage all the others.
你廢話還真是多 知道麼 漢克
I think you're full of crap, you know that, Hank?
是麼
Really?
老天
Jesus.
幸虧那不是我們
Thank God that ain't us.
早告訴過你我們會沒事吧
Told you.
博茨 讓他們做好防禦
Boots, spread them out and put them on a line.
一班  原地駐防
Set up a perimeter! First Squad!
漢克 找個洞 行
Hank? Find me a pole. Yeah.
我們把旗升起來
Let's put this flag up.
看準了
Watch it.
就這兒
Right over here.
就這兒 很好 很好 這兒 這兒
Right here. That's good. That's good. Right here, right here.
抓住那頭沒有 拿穩了
Got that end? Hold that steady.
林勃
Lindberg.
嘿 誰有繩子 這兒有
Hey, who's got rope? Right here.
給我 對 好
Give me something. Yeah, good.
行麼
That work?
干吧
Do it, fellas.
保持住
Keep it coming.
陸戰隊！陸戰隊！
USMC! USMC!
USMC 為美海軍陸戰隊略稱
靠  看那
Shit, look at that!
天 看那
Jeez, look at that.
臥倒！ 找掩護！
Get down! Take cover!
射擊
Cover with that.30!
當心 下方20碼 漢克！ 看到沒有？
Watch it! Twenty yards down, Hank! You see them?
大約20碼  左側 林勃 去拿噴火器來
I got about 20 yards, left side. Lindberg, get the flamethrower!
博茨 看到沒有 掩護右翼！
Boots, you see them? Cover right!
下方大約20碼 發現一個！ 看到沒有？
About 20 yards down! Duck one! You see them?
繼續掩護
Keep the cover on!
二班 看到沒有？
Second Squad, you see them?
手榴彈給我
Get me some grenades!
看到了
I see them!
你看到了？
You see them?
右翼 轉向左側！
Right flank, over to the right!
掩護我 我下去看看
Cover me, I'm going down!
小心 伊基
Careful, Iggy.
慢點下
Easy.
目標清除
All clear!
好的 小伙們 誰想出名
Okay, guys, who wants to be famous?
是 長官  我立即去辦 長官
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
他媽的  斯坦克 長官？
God damn it. Strank! Sir?
他們想把電話線架到山頂去
They want a phone line run up to the top of the mountain.
猜就是讓我們去
Let me guess, they picked us.
二排 我們走 運動一下
Second Platoon, let's go. Get some exercise.
走啦  爬起來
Let's go! Get off your ass.
我靠
Oh, shit!
希望它還能用 因為我不會借給你用的
Hope it still works, 'cause you're not getting mine!
我拍到福萊斯特號了！ 好啊
Get Forrestal! All right, then.
我不知道那是誰的主意 參謀長先生
I don't know whose idea it was, Mr. Secretary.
真他媽天才 我想要那面旗 霍蘭
Well, it was goddamn brilliant. I want that flag, Holland.
霍蘭·史密斯 第五兩棲軍軍長 硫磺島地面戰的總指揮
記下我的話 升起那面旗
Mark my words, raising that son-of-a-bitch
意味著陸戰隊能再存在500年
means a Marine Corps for the next 500 years.
我想要那面旗
I want that flag.
是 長官 我會確保沒人動它的
Yes, sir. I'll make sure no one touches it.
相信我
You can count on me.
操他媽的 旗子是屬於全營人的
Fuck that. That flag belongs to the men in this battalion.
那婊子養的還以為 我們提著腦袋打下這
That son-of-a-bitch thinks that our men died taking this ground
就是為了把我們的旗子 送給政客去掛在他牆上麼
so we could hand over our flag to some politician to pin to his wall?
真他媽腦子燒壞了
He's out of his goddamn mind!
把那面旗給我拿下來 另找一面替上它
Get me that flag, and find another one to replace it.
你這不是耍我麼
You've gotta be shitting me.
蓋格南！
Gagnon!
趕緊給我滾過來
Get your ass over here.
嘿 夥計 怎麼樣
Hey. Hi, fellas. How's it going?
你錯過一次絕佳拍照機會啊 喬
Missed a beautiful shot, Joe.
這得怨天氣
It's that kind of day.
嘿 麥克 這兒的視野真不錯
Hey, Mike. Hell of a view, Lieutenant.
中尉！
Lieutenant!
上校說他想要那面旗
Captain says he wants that flag.
他想要這面旗？
He wants this flag?
是 長官
Yes, sir.
我們剛把那玩意兒升上去 是 長官
We just put the damn thing up. Yes, sir.
缺旗子用是麼
Some kind of flag shortage?
他想讓你用這一面替上
He wants you to put this one up instead.
嘿  麥克
Hey, Mike.
幫個忙把這個升上去 行不行
Do me a favor and put this up, will you?
好的
Yes, sir.
好 先找個洞
All right, let's find a pole.
把旗降下來
Take the flag down, boys.
上校的命令
Captain's orders.
聽到他說的了吧 咱們動手吧
You heard him, let's do it.
好的
There you go.
洛蒂  真沉啊
Lordy, she's a heavy one.
好 把這個掛好
All right, hang on. Put this on.
在上面視野真不錯
One hell of a view, huh?
是啊  換我也這麼說
Good view from up here. Yes, I'd say so myself.
行了
All right.
我站這兒沒擋住你吧 喬? 沒 沒問題 謝謝
Not in your way here, am I, Joe? Nah, I'm fine, thanks.
嘿 醫生 幫個忙行麼
Hey, Doc, you wanna give us a hand here?
要開始插旗了
Oh, Jesus, Bill, here she goes.
準備好沒？
Ready? Ready?
開始了
Let's go.
拍到沒有
You get it?
不知道 希望能拍到臉
I don't know. I wish I could've seen their faces.
沒人知道我們升了第二面旗
Nobody even noticed that second flag going up.
大家僅僅看了那張照片 然後就開始自己發揮想像
Everybody saw that damn picture and made up their own story about it.
但是你爸爸和其他人 知道他們都做了什麼
But your dad and the others knew what they had done
以及沒做什麼
and what they had not done.
想想如果你的朋友都快死了
All your friends dying,
救過別人一命的 確實應該被稱作英雄
it's hard not to be called a hero for saving somebody's life.
但要是就樹了根桿子呢
But for putting up a pole?
你這是在開玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding.
嘿！這可是好多人費了好長 時間才搭起來的
Hey! It took a lot of talented folks a long time to make that thing.
等到今晚  燈光往上一打
Just wait till tonight when it's lit properly
看台上幾千觀眾鼓掌歡呼
and there's thousands of cheering people in the stands.
到時候看起來可就（比現在） 好多了
It's gonna look a lot better.
到時候  大燈熄滅
So, stadium lights come down,
聚光燈亮起 你們就上場
spotlight comes up and you get your cue.
你們拿著旗子衝到這東西頂上 把旗插上
You charge up this thing with the flag, you plant it at the top.
然後你們微笑 揮手 插旗用的洞是現成的
You smile, you wave. You know the drill.
你想讓我們把旗子插到 這坨紙漿糊上？
You want us to plant the flag on a pile of papier-mache.
嘿  那就是個面子活兒
Hey, that's show biz.
盡量按著當初的隊形站在上面
And try and stand how you stood the first time you planted it.
你們就…知道吧…假裝 那三個人也在身邊
Just, you know, pretend the other three guys are with you.
那些死人
The dead guys.
是  是的
Yeah. Yeah.
好  沒問題了
Okay, not a problem.
很好
Good.
但我們怎麼想像漢克 站在那
But where do we imagine Hank is standing?
你說什麼？
Sorry?
他當時又沒升旗
Well, seeing that he wasn't there,
給他留出個位置很難
it'll be kind of hard for us to leave a space for him.
我想你知道他當時站在哪 你向他母親指出過的
I think you know exactly where he was. You pointed him out to his mother.
什麼狗屁東西
This is bullshit.
我升過一次那玩意了 我可不想再搞一遍
I planted that damn thing once, and I'm not doing it again.
海因斯！ 看在老天面上 回來吧
Hayes! Oh, for Christ's sake.
海因斯  海因斯  趕緊給我回來 不然我打你報告
Hayes. Hayes, get your ass back here or you're going on report.
海因斯！
Hayes!
你也不管管?
You wanna do your damn job?
放開我！放開我！
Let go of me! Let go of me!
來吧！
Come on!
他和我一起的！
He's with me!
嘿 他是和我一起的！
Hey, he's with me!
退後！ 先生  我們是一起的  好麼? 他是和我一起的
Back off! Sir, he's with me. Okay? He's with me.
艾拉 把椅子放下！
Ira, put the goddamn chair down!
把椅子放下 把椅子放下 艾拉！
Put the chair down, son! Put the chair down, Ira!
讓他們先把棍子放下！
Tell them drop their sticks!
艾拉  他們是警察 他們應該帶著警棍
Ira, they're cops, they're supposed to have nightsticks.
但是你不能在大街中間 拿著椅子亂掄
You're not supposed to be in the street swinging a chair.
冷靜點 先生 請回過頭來看
Calm down, son. Sir, turn around, please.
那邊那張海報看到了麼？ 堶掖怮嶀@個人就是他
That poster right there? The one on the end, that's him.
是他麼？ 是的 先生 你看過報紙上的報道了麼
That's him? Yes, sir. You read the papers?
老天
Christ.
又他媽一個發瘋的英雄 趕緊帶他走
We got another fucking hero. Get him out of here.
你去行麼 行 先生
Can you do that? Yes, sir.
把椅子給我放下 我們走
Put the goddamn chair down. And let's go.
是你先挑頭的麼？
Did you start this?
他不招待我！
He didn't serve me!
規矩又不是我定的 我們不招待印第安人
I don't make the rules. We don't serve Indians.
他得好好睡一覺
He needs to go sleep it off.
到戰士體育場
Soldier Field.
你聽到沒有？
You hear that?
那是什麼聲音？
What the hell is that?
我聽不清
I can't figure it out.
小心點
Keep an eye out.
好像是從上面那兒傳出來的
It sounds like it's coming from up there.
手榴彈炸的
They're using grenades.
他們自殺了
They're killing themselves.
艾拉  走吧
Ira, let's go.
來吧
Come on.
走吧 艾拉 來吧
Let's go, Ira. Come on.
謝天謝地 老天 看看你 酋長
Thank God. Jesus. Look at you, Chief.
你找到他了
You found him.
我靠  你怎麼偏偏今天（喝醉）
Holy shit. You would have to pick today.
范德格堣玼S將軍都來了 樂隊都他媽開始演奏了
Vandegrift is here with enough brass to start a fucking band.
趕緊走吧 你還能走麼
Come on, let's go. Can you walk?
還行 能自己走麼
Yes, sir. By yourself?
好吧  聽好了 我不管你是不是扶著他
All right, look. I don't care if you have to carry him
反正把他弄到山頂去 把旗子插上 別他媽演砸了
get him to the top, plant that flag, and don't fucking fall off.
叫他把行頭換上 我盡量 給你拖時間  動作快點
Get him in his stuff. I'll stall these guys for as long as I can. Hurry up.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
現在有請 硫磺島的英雄們！
And now, the heroes of lwo Jima!
找掩護
Cover!
哈倫！
Harlon!
哈倫！帶你的火力組到那個位置
Harlon! Get your fire team up in that position!
收到
O'Hare!
第一火力組！
First Fire Team!
快散開！
Work around!
BAR（勃朗寧步槍手） 你 到崖底下去！
BAR, you, on the side of the ridge!
火力掩護   上 上 上
Covering fire, boys, go, go, go!
傑克遜 帶你的小組 掩護左翼
Jackson, work your team around to the left!
掩護！
Cover!
左翼！左翼！
Left flank! Left flank!
富蘭克林 噶斯特 檢查戰果
Franklin, Gust, go check it out!
小心誤傷
Hustle up, boys!
我們打中他了
We got them!
清除！
Clear!
今天倒霉到家了
One hell of an experience.
出發！
Move out!
馬上停火！ 那是我們的人！ 你瞄準的是我們的人！
Cease fire! They're my men! You're targeting our men!
你瞄準的是我們的…
You're targeting our...
再拿一部電台來
Get me another radio!
中士?中士！
Sergeant? Sergeant!
麥克！
Mike!
麥克 麥克 麥克
Mike, Mike, Mike.
麥克?麥克
Mike? Mike.
醫生在哪?
Hey, where's Doc?
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
糟糕
Oh, shit.
他呼吸怎麼樣 哈倫 讓一讓
How's his breathing? Harlon, move, buddy.
嘿 麥克 麥克麥克 能聽到 我們說話麼
Hey, Mike. Mike, Mike, can you hear us?
我沒事
It's okay.
挺住 麥克
Come on, Mike.
麥克？麥克？能聽到我們麼？
Mike? Mike, can you hear us?
好了 大家出發
All right, let's go!
行動！這堨瘚鼠嵾惘洵B
Move out!
我去找副擔架
I'm gonna get a stretcher.
把他抬走運回國去
Let's take him down, move him off the beach.
女士們先生們 有請硫磺島英雄們！
Ladies and gentlemen, the heroes of lwo Jima!
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
漢克！
Hank!
醫生  他們把我殺了
Doc, they killed me.
哈倫！
Harlon!
醫生
Doc,
他們把我殺了
they killed me.
挺住 哈倫 哈倫 堅持住
Come on, Harlon. Harlon, stay with me.
富蘭克林！
Franklin!
我沒事 艾拉
I'm fine, Ira.
醫務兵！
Corpsman!
他去哪了? 誰?
Where'd he go? Who?
他剛才還在這兒的 伊基 他去哪了?
The guy who was right here, Ignatowski. Where did he go?
你找錯地方了吧 我才沒找錯地方！
I think you jumped in the wrong hole. I didn't jump in the wrong hole!
剛剛他還在這 現在他去哪了?
He was right here, now where the hell is he?
伊基！
Iggy!
你閉嘴吧  你想讓全島日本人 都向我們開火麼?
You shut up. You want every Jap on the island shooting at us?
伊基！
Iggy!
它是開著的麼?
Does it open?
伊基！
Iggy!
伊基 你在下面麼?
Iggy, are you down there?
伊基！
Iggy!
分不清他是誰  不過肯定是我們的人
Can't tell who it is, but he's one of ours.
我得在外面先吐一會兒
I had to go outside to throw up.
瞧瞧他們都對這可憐的傢伙 做了些什麼
Look what they did to the poor son-of-a-bitch.
酋長 你沒事吧?
You okay, Chief?
別把這事放在心上
Just let it go.
如果這樣還橇不開他們的錢包 我就沒招了
If that doesn't pry open their wallets, nothing will.
老天爺  他喝醉了
Jesus Christ, he's drunk.
該死的印第安人
Goddamn Indians.
來 酋長 我們回家
Come on, Chief. Let's get you home.
戰士體育場：獻給服役的人們
我聽到的可不是這樣 我問過一圈了 我又不蠢
That's not what I hear. I called around, I'm not stupid.
他從一開始就喝醉了
He's been drunk since he started this damn tour,
純粹譁眾取寵
making a spectacle of himself.
居然還在接待宴會上摟著那個 可憐的女人又哭又嚎
Just about choked that poor woman at the reception, blubbering.
老天 看看你們手下人的德性
Jesus Christ, you're supposed to be watching these men.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
他讓我們看起來就像個笨蛋
Well, he's making us look like regular asses.
我絕無冒犯之意 長官
Well, with all due respect, sir,
他一開始就不想做這次巡迴籌款
he never wanted to come on this trip in the first place.
（當時）他又踢又打 大喊大叫 我們好不容易才把他從船上拉下來
We had to pull him, kicking and screaming, off that boat.
他想跟他的戰友在一起
He wants to be with his unit.
他還有什麼戰友？ 全他媽死了
What unit? They're all fucking dead.
他就是靠喝酒嘔吐 來紀念他們的麼？
This is how he honors those men? By drinking and throwing up, and...
他不是想回去麼？ 好 我們就讓他回去
You know what? He wants it, great, we'll send him back.
叫他收拾好行李 搭今天的火車走人 他不配穿上這身制服！
Get him packed and on a train today. He's an embarrassment to the uniform.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
交給我做
I'll do it.
好啊 不 其實… 很好 我就是那麼想的
Yeah, no, that's... That's good. That's what I want.
我知道那是好事
I know it's a good thing,
巡迴籌款 因為我們需要錢
raising the money and that, 'cause we need it.
但是
But,
我受不了別人叫我英雄
I can't take them calling me a hero.
我所做的不過是努力不被打中
All I did was try not to get shot.
我見過的
Some of the things I saw done,
還有做過的事
things I did,
沒什麼可自豪的 你明白麼？
they weren't things to be proud of, you know?
麥克…
Mike...
麥克才是英雄
Mike was a hero.
你見過他麼？
You ever meet him?
沒有
No.
他是我見過最好的陸戰隊員
Best Marine I ever met.
酋長 我覺得 如果是麥克 而不是你坐在這堛爾
You know, Chief, I think if Mike was sitting here instead of you
他也會這麼評價自己的
he'd be saying the same thing about himself,
說自己不是英雄
not being a hero.
可能吧
Maybe.
他是個好人
He was a good guy.
但我覺得 他看到我現在的樣子以後
But I think that he would be ashamed of me,
會替我感到丟人的
seeing me the way I am.
回去之前我能看看我媽媽麼
Think I could see my ma before they ship me off?
就一眼 行麼 看看媽媽
Think they'd do that? See my ma?
抱歉 艾拉
I'm sorry, Ira.
你跟她的孩子們就這麼說
We got stories now to tell our kids, I guess.
保持低調
Keep your head down.
發車
All aboard.
好運 酋長
Good luck, Chief.
在那之後我見過他一次
I think I saw him once after that.
大概是在戰後六七年吧
It was maybe six or seven years after the war.
我當時是推銷員 經常開車
I was working as a salesman, doing a lot of driving.
有次我向西橫穿得克薩斯
I was driving west across Texas.
當時一心想回家 正找方向呢
I was just trying to get where I was going so I could get home.
然後我看到他 在路邊想搭車
And I saw this guy hitchhiking on the side of the road.
一瞬間 我想到可能是他
And, for a second, I thought it might've been him.
我現在經常後悔當時 為什麼不停下來 但我當時很急
I always regret that I didn't stop, but I was in a hurry.
而且他是個印第安人
And he was an Indian.
我們總對報紙說 當時艾拉執意
We always told the press that Ira insisted
要回部隊繼續戰鬥
that he was going back to fight with his unit
這至少算是部分真實的吧
which was at least partially true, but
但最後報紙頭條出來卻不是這樣
that isn't what got the headlines.
我們訂婚了
We're engaged.
我失陪一會兒 親愛的
Excuse me a minute, darling.
嘿 醫生? 嗯?
Hey, Doc? Yeah?
有時間麼? 嗯
Got a minute? Yeah.
車上見
I'll see you at the car.
你聽說過我就要結婚了麼？ 聽說了 瑞尼 那太好了
You hear I'm getting married? I did, Rene. That's great.
是啊 她要求的 她等了我這麼久
Yeah, it's something she wants. She waited for me all this time.
她還不習慣這一切 但她可是個好女孩
She's not used to all this, but she's a good girl.
我確定你會很幸福的
I'm sure you'll be very happy.
我在考慮是不是請你當我的伴郎
So, I was wondering if you'd be my best man.
我？
Me?
你在家奡N沒有什麼人麼？ 比如叫一個兄弟來當？
Don't you have somebody at home, a buddy, you'd rather ask?
嗯  不太多
Well, I didn't really make many.
他們不能去是因為… 嗯 我基本沒怎麼跟他們說過話
The ones who didn't go, it's... Well, it's hard to even talk to them.
知道麼？
You know?
哦 知道了
Yeah, I know.
我…我很榮幸
I'd be proud to.
謝謝
Thank you.
我得馬上把她拉走 要不然她可能會說
I better go drag her away from them before she announces
我會成為通用汽車公司老總 什麼的
I'm gonna be president of General Motors or something.
好的
All right.
祝賀你 非常感謝  謝謝
Congratulations. Thank you so much. Thank you.
瑞尼 你真幸運
Rene, you're a lucky man.
笑一笑 蓋格南先生 說茄子
Big smile, Mrs. Gagnon! Say cheese!
我沒法抱怨 因為媒體喜歡他們
I couldn't complain because the press loved them,
相關報道越多 軍債賣得越好
so they wrote more articles and people bought more bonds.
巡迴籌款還在繼續 只剩下了瑞尼和你父親
The tour went on with just Rene and your dad.
真正的英雄是那些 沒能從硫磺島活著回來的人們
And the true heroes are the men who didn't make it home from lwo Jima,
是那些死在硫磺島戰役 和其他戰役中的人們
the men who died at lwo Jima and in other campaigns.
購買更多的戰爭債券吧
We ask that you honor the memory of those men
我們將籍此告慰戰歿者的亡靈 萬眾一心 贏得這場戰爭
by buying the war bonds and helping us to win this war.
謝謝
Thank you.
一個城市接著一個城市 這鬼差事沒完沒了
City after city, I thought the damn thing'd never end.
「照片是當時拍的」的流言 也開始流傳
And this rumor kept going around that the photograph had been staged.
我記得你爸爸告訴他們
I remember your dad telling them
說他也很想知道 是誰拍了那張照片
that he wished he'd known he was having his picture taken
他說他就算挖地三尺 也要把拍照人找出來
because he would've ducked the hell out of it.
當時是誰的主意？ 是誰安排你們擺拍的？
Whose idea was it? Who wanted to stage the thing?
說說嘛  那是你麼
Come on, it was you?
照片是擺拍的事是真的麼 醫生？
Was there truth to the rumor that that picture was staged, Doc?
說吧 醫生? 你能回答那個問題麼?
Come on! Doc? Can you answer that?
我還記得你爸爸中彈的消息傳過來的情形 當時好像天都要塌下來了
I remember when your dad got shot. All hell was busting loose.
人們回家看到那張照片以後
People back home saw that picture
就認為只要我們打下折缽山 就結束了
and thought it was over when we took Suribachi.
我們那是做夢
We wished.
當時我們正被壓制
Anyways, we're pinned down.
迫擊炮 榴彈炮 機槍
Mortars, shells, machine guns.
子彈 彈片橫飛
Fire coming from every which direction, right?
然後我們聽到有人喊 「醫務兵倒下了」
And we hear somebody call, "Corpsman down."
醫務兵倒下了！
Corpsman down!
他的喉嚨鮮血噴涌 醫生用盡了一切手段
Blood was spurting out of his throat, and Doc was doing everything he could.
醫務兵向上望著他
And the Corpsman looks up at him
脖子中彈 九死一生
and he knows what this means, to be shot in the neck.
他自己應該知道這一點
He knows he's dying, you can see that.
但是
But still
他的眼堨是祈求 祈求醫生能救他一命
in his eyes, he's pleading with Doc to save his life.
但是醫生無能為力
And Doc can't.
醫生 你沒事吧? 嗯 我沒事
You okay, Doc? Yeah, I'm fine.
這還叫沒事 沒什麼大事
Yeah, you look fine. I'm okay.
趴著別動 我去給你找擔架來
Keep down, all right? I'm gonna go get a stretcher.
好
Okay.
醫務兵 醫務兵！
Corpsman. Corpsman!
看在上帝面上！ 醫務兵！
For God sake, Corpsman!
醫務兵?
Corpsman?
醫務兵
Corpsman.
炮彈來襲！
Incoming!
讓我看看
Let me see.
沒那麼糟糕 你會沒事的
It's not that bad. You're gonna be okay. All right?
堅持住 看著我
Just stay with me. Look at me.
後來我們花了半小時才找到你爸 他差點流血過多而死
Took us a half-hour to find your dad. He could've bled to death.
放下
Coming down.
謝謝
Thanks.
老兵可能會告訴你說他們是如何 自己中彈  但卻不想拋棄戰友的
Vets'll tell you about being hit but not wanting to leave their buddies.
通常講 他們都是在撒謊
Usually, they're lying.
隨便找個理由你就能 拍屁股走人
You'll take any excuse to get out of there.
但當時確實發生了
But it happens.
你感覺到 自己讓他們失望了
You get the feeling you're letting them down.
這我從你爸爸臉上就看得出來
I could see that in your dad's face.
他只想離開 他看夠了這一切
He wanted to go, he'd seen enough.
但他不想扔下我們
But he didn't want to leave us.
你爸爸 真的是一個大好人
Now, he was a hell of a good man, your dad.
是啊
Yeah.
我們坐在海灘上的時候 聽到了巨大的轟鳴聲
While we were sitting there on the beach, we heard this great roar.
於是我們抬頭看
And we looked up.
那是第一架降落在硫磺島上的 飛機 後來還有幾千架次
That was the first of thousands of landings on lwo.
看看 嗯
Look at that. Yeah.
怎麼樣
How about that.
我一會在回來 好麼
I'm gonna head back, all right?
好運
Good luck.
拿下那座島 我們就可以少死很多人 （指提前結束戰爭）
That island saved a lot of lives.
很多很多人
A lot of lives.
我沒什麼可說的了
I don't know what else to tell you.
巡迴籌款結束以後 我爸終於可以做手術
After the bond tour my dad finally got his operation.
他回家的時候 戰爭已經結束了
By the time he got home the war was over.
他做的第一件事 就是向我媽求婚
First thing he did was ask my mom to marry him.
艾拉嘗試著繼續生活 忘掉從前的一切
Ira tried to get on with his life and put it all behind him.
牌子上寫的是：全美印第安人大會
謝謝大家今天邀請我到這
Thank you for having me here today.
站在這麼多強大的人面前 令我感到榮耀
It's an honor to be in front of such a strong people.
因為戰爭
Because of the war
白人會大大加深對印第安人的瞭解
white men will understand Indians a lot better.
世界也會變得更加美好
And it's going to be a better world.
但生活對他另有安排
But life had other plans for him.
你是…你是他  對麼
You're... You're him, aren't you?
你就是那個英雄  是麼
You're the hero, right?
太好了  好  孩子們 去合個影吧
Great. All right, kids, go get your picture taken.
太好了 太好了
Oh, that's great. That's great.
好 現在說茄子
All right, now say cheese.
茄子！
Cheese!
太好了！好的 嘿  多謝你啊 多謝
That's great! Okay. Hey, thanks a lot. Thanks.
來吧 那可是個英雄 孩子們
Come on. That's a hero, kids.
英雄  搬一下這個筐吧 太重了我搬不動
Hero, lift this basket, will you? It's too heavy for me.
瑞尼試著兌現他在巡迴籌款中 所收到的承諾
Rene tried to take advantage of those offers he'd received on the bond tour.
是的  G-A-G-N-O-N
Yes. G-A-G-N-O-N.
對 讀作瑞尼 瑞尼 是的
Right. Pronounced Rene. Rene, yes.
好的 上星期我就打過電話了 好的 那麼 蓋格南先生
Okay, I actually called last week. Yes. Okay, yes. Mr. Gagnon.
我已經把你的信息轉給了田納科先生 他會給你打過去的
I gave Mr. Tennack your message. I'm sure he'll call you.
好的 好的
Okay. All right.
謝謝
Thank you.
但他只是昨日英雄了
But he was yesterday's hero.
他甚至向當地警察局申請工作
He even applied for a job at the local police station.
他們說他還不合格
They said he wasn't qualified.
和女友波琳在工廠幹了一段之後 他跳了幾次槽
After working the factory with Pauline he tried a few things
最後做了看門人終此一生
but spent the rest of his life as a janitor.
至於艾拉…
But Ira...
艾拉！有訪客！
Ira! You got a visitor.
艾拉總能上新聞
Ira always made the news.
亞利桑那州 馬堿鴝玷勾給謏
我也不知他何以至此 但有一天他就那麼被釋放了
I could never find out why he did it, but one day Ira just took off.
他邊走邊攔車走了1300多英里
He walked and hitched over 1,300 miles
從亞利桑那走到得克薩斯
from Arizona to Texas.
最後找到了正在田里耕地的 哈倫·布勞克的父親
He found Harlon Block's father working his field.
他的妻子貝爾一聽到哈倫戰死 的消息 就和他分居了
His wife, Belle, had left him soon after they discovered Harlon died.
她一直都沒有原諒他 讓自己的兒子上戰場的決定
She never forgave him for letting her son go off to war.
艾拉告訴了他真相
And Ira told him the truth,
是他的兒子參與了當時的升旗
that it had been his son who raised the flag with them,
是他的兒子上了照片
his son in the photograph.
然後 艾拉只是轉身離去
And then he just turned and walked away.
雖然對於參與升旗他早已看淡
Though the flag-raising meant nothing to him,
但他知道對於哈倫一家 這意味著什麼
he somehow knew it would mean everything to them.
謝謝你打來
Thanks for calling.
貝爾知道真相之後不久
Just as Belle knew all along.
媒體也得以知曉
The press soon found out
打電話給漢克的母親說照片上 沒有她的孩子
and called Hank's mom with the news that it wasn't her son after all.
他們最後一次見面
The last time they all saw each other
是在海軍陸戰隊戰爭紀念碑 落成儀式上
was at the unveiling of the Marine Corps War Memorial.
儘管漢克參與了硫磺島上第一面 美國國旗的升旗儀式
And even though he planted the first flag above lwo Jima,
他的父母卻沒有被邀請
Hank's mother and father weren't invited.
艾拉
Ira.
見到你真好 艾拉
It's good to see you, Ira.
雕像真不錯
Hell of a statue.
在那之後不久 有人找到了艾拉
It wasn't long after that that they found Ira.
報紙上說他死於暴曬（與曝光是同一個詞） 沒有人去驗屍瞭解死因
The papers said he died of exposure. There was no autopsy.
當時 差不多同一時間
It was about that same time
一天早晨  我爸爸走進車
when my father got in his car early one morning
告訴我媽媽說他有事情要做
telling my mom he had something to do.
他開車去了威斯康星州另一端 伊基的母親所在的的一個鎮子
He drove to a town on the other side of Wisconsin where Iggy's mom lived.
她獲知兒子的死訊以後
Ever since she heard the news about her son
她就一直試圖找出她兒子的死因 沒有人告訴她
she'd been trying to find out how he died, and no one would tell her.
我不知道當時他都對她說了些什麼
I never found out what he told her,
但是我差不多敢保證她聽到的 不是真相
but I can pretty much guarantee it wasn't the truth.
我媽媽常常問他什麼讓他惦念
My mother would ask him what was troubling him.
但他從來不說
He would never say.
每年快到陣亡將士紀念日的時候
And every year, as it got close to Memorial Day,
記者們就會打電話來 要採訪我爸爸
the reporters would start calling asking to interview my father.
不 很抱歉 他正在加拿大釣魚
No, I'm sorry. He's fishing in Canada.
我們總是統一口徑
We were always instructed to say the same thing.
好的 謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
麥克坎德勒先生退休後
When Mr. McCandless retired,
爸爸買下了他戰後工作過的 一家殯儀館
my father bought the funeral home where he'd worked since coming home.
從此經營生意 養活家人 終此一生
He spent the rest of his life running the business and raising his family.
他從來不向我們提戰爭 和升旗的事情
He never spoke about the war or about the flag-raising,
隻字不提
never told us anything.
我聽到任何與那有關的事情 已經是在他過世以後了
The first time I heard any of these stories was after he died.
伊基在哪？老天
Where is he? Oh, God.
他不在這 爸爸
He's not here, Dad.
他死了
He died.
誰？誰死了？
Who? Who died?
伊基
Iggy.
老天 可憐的伊基
Christ, poor Iggy.
我好多年沒見他了
I hadn't thought of him for years.
你是怎麼知道伊基的？
How do you know about Iggy?
你病倒的時候 喊的是他的名字
You were calling for him, when you collapsed.
我其實也不是在找伊奇
I wasn't looking for Iggy.
我是在找你
I was looking for you.
我想…
I wanted to...
我想告訴你 我很抱歉 我這個父親做得不夠好
I wanted to tell you I'm sorry I wasn't a better father.
跟你交流不夠
Talked to you more.
我只是…
I just...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉?
Sorry?
你是世界上最好的父親
You were the best father a man could have.
我告訴過你我們游泳的事麼
Did I ever tell you they took us swimming?
沒有 爸爸
No, Dad.
我們當時升完旗以後 就下山
After we planted the flag, we came down off the mountain
他們讓我們游泳
and they let us swim.
那是最有意思的了
It was the funniest thing.
所有那些戰鬥都暫時拋到腦後
All this fighting
我們就跳進水  玩得像孩子…
and we were jumping around in the water like kids.
我就是這樣來記住伊基的
That's the way I remember Iggy now.
最後我終於發現 他可能是對的
I finally came to the conclusion that maybe he was right.
也許本來就沒有英雄
Maybe there's no such thing as heroes.
也許本來他們就是像我爸爸 一樣的凡人
Maybe there are just people like my dad.
我也終於明白
I finally came to understand
為什麼他們受不了被人稱作英雄
why they were so uncomfortable being called heroes.
英雄是我們創造出來的 我們需要英雄
Heroes are something we create, something we need.
這樣我們就能夠理解那個 以前讓人感到費解的問題
It's a way for us to understand what is almost incomprehensible,
就是人們為什麼為我們付出 那麼重大的犧牲
how people could sacrifice so much for us.
但是對於我的父親和他的弟兄們
But for my dad and these men,
他們承擔生命危險 甘冒槍林彈雨
the risks they took, the wounds they suffered,
為的不過是他們的戰友
they did that for their buddies.
他們為國而戰 但是為友而死
They may have fought for their country, but they died for their friends.
為了他們那些身前身後 的普通戰友們
For the man in front, for the man beside them.
如果我們想要真正銘記這些人
And if we wish to truly honor these men,
就應該還他們以本色
we should remember them the way they really were,
正如我父親所做的那樣
the way my dad remembered them.
快過來 醫生
Come on, Doc!
約翰·佈雷德利 （醫生）
瑞尼·蓋格南
艾拉·海耶斯
凱斯·伊奇
麥克·考特尼
拉爾夫·伊格納托斯基（伊基）
亨利·漢森（漢克）
1945年2月23日，海軍陸戰隊五師二十八團 二營的官兵在此樹起星條旗